hi this is dr steph flick with coastal
integrative health care in edgewater
palm coast and debary
and today i'm going to share with you
some really good information
before you pick a health insurance plan
this year right now we're in open
enrollment
i wanted to give you some tips and a
point of view from a doctor's
perspective
with the types of plans that we see so a
lot of patients come into the office
and they are adamant and sure that they
have picked the best insurance plan
and that their insurance will pay for
everything that they don't have to worry
about it at
all and turns out once you've actually
verified the insurance there's very
limited benefits
so they've been told by an insurance
salesperson that
this plan is going to be the same as
medicare you can go to the same doctors
you can get the same services
it's going to save you a lot of money on
your monthly premiums and it's going to
cover the same
services that's not usually the case
during open enrollment
it's important to know is your doctor a
network with this insurance
but also what services do they actually
cover here's an example of some medicare
cards
so this is the new one that came out
this year and this is the old one that
we were used to seeing
red white and blue cards medicare is
you know a federal insurance plan for
people 65 and older or those that are
disabled
and we found that this plan is if you
keep the basic medicare plan even
without a supplement or a secondary
tends to be one of the strongest best
plans out there they're not going to
limit
what doctors you can see they're going
to have a majority of services are going
to be available
and so we we always like the medicare
plans from our perspective
as a medical office we will see that
patients tend to have the best benefits
the hmo plans the ppo plans the
replacement plans any medicare
replacement plan with florida healthcare
humana gold plus
united healthcare there's a ton of them
out there
those have very limited benefits
oftentimes they require you to go
get a referral from your primary care
doctor or from somewhere else
and then when they come into our office
they may cover one or two services
but not everything that you need as a
patient
so the important thing is you should be
deciding your health care
not your insurance company your health
is your responsibility
not your insurance companies so if they
don't cover something you're going to be
forced to pay
that out of pocket and that's not you
know it is what it is and you're
responsible
for it but bottom line is you shouldn't
rely on your insurance company to take
care of your health in the first place
anyway
i hope you found this useful if you have
questions about insurances what
insurances we take
and the benefits of them give us a call
at any of our locations we'll be happy
to answer them for you or do a
verification
but we do take most insurance as almost
all of them so
hopefully you found this useful share it
with your friends anyone else that you
may know
and we're here to help you out take care